A large batch of goods
一大批货
is stuck in inventory.
压在手里
I'm not able to sell them out.
卖不出去
Also, the cash flow
现金流
has been cut off.
也断了
So I couldn't
银行贷款
repay any of the loans.
也没法还
I couldn't even afford
更没有钱
to expand
去拓展渠道
businesses or sales.
打开销路了
I get the picture of the situation
您说的这个情况
you described.
我大概了解了
This is indeed a significant challenge
这对咱们厂来说确实
for your company.
是一个很大的痛苦
Mr. Sun,
孙厂长
if you still have faith in me,
您要是还算相信我
would it be possible for me to review
我方不方便看一下
your financial statements?
咱们的财务报表啊
For this whole thing,
这件事情
no one should be blamed.
谁也怪不着
I understand that
我知道
not repaying loans
不还贷款
is not a sustainable solution.
也不是长久之计
I could only delay it one day
我只能拖一天
at a time.
算一天
So I've rushed to acquire
所以我就
this batch of raw materials.
抓紧进了这批原材料
I have an export order
我下个月有一个
coming up next month.
出口单子
If it went through,
这单做成了
a portion could be repaid.
多少也能给你们还一点
To be frank,
这要我说呀
every time my guys come to see you,
他们每次来找您的时候
you really don't need to avoid them.
您真不至于都躲着不见
What's the point of meeting them?
见有什么用啊
You're just here to pressure me
你们不外乎就是催我
to repay the loan
早点还款
and interest sooner.
还利息
I might as well use this time
有这时间
to go out and hustle
我还不如出去跑跑
for some orders.
跑跑单子
Then,
谈成了
I would repay you a bit more.
也能给你们多还上一些
And I can also ensure my workers
也能给我自己的工人
continue to get paid.
多发一天工资
It makes
您说的
perfect sense.
我觉得都对
But there's one thing
但是有一点
you've got wrong.
您说错了
We won't
我们银行
just pressure you for repayment.
不是只会催你们还款
We genuinely want to help you
我们也想帮您
resolve the issues
去解决问题
and get through this obstacle.
渡过这个难关
Mr. Sun,
孙厂长
I actually have a solution.
我倒是有一个办法
I'm not sure if you
不知道您
would be open to try it.
愿不愿意试一下
I can get
我可以再给你们
another loan for you.
申请一笔贷款
However, it must
但是这个资金
be allocated to
必须要用在
sales expansion.
销售渠道的拓展上
Is this possible?
这能不能成为一条出路
Although this is
虽然咱们
the first time we've met,
今天是第一次见
I'm willing to trust you.
但我愿意相信您
In this challenging situation,
在这种困境之下
you've managed to keep
还能把财务报表
financial statements in order.
做得这么规规矩矩的人
That's actually quite rare.
其实不多见了
And I just noticed
而且刚刚我也看到了
that in such heavy rain,
下这么大雨
you personally led a team of workers
您亲自带着这么多工人
to protect raw materials.
去救那些原材料
I believe
我相信
that you truly care about
您一定是对这个厂
this factory.
真正上心的
I wanna lend you a hand.
我也想拉你一把
Mr. Ji,
纪总
if you can
如果
provide us with a loan,
如果你真能给我们贷款
you will be our lifesaver.
就是我的救命恩人哪
As long as we have sufficient cash flow,
我们厂只要现金流充裕
we can get back on our feet.
我们厂就可以滚动起来
We'll have a way out.
我们就有活路了
Much appreciate it!
感谢
Mr. Sun.
孙厂长
Thank you so much!
谢谢
Please don't thank me just yet.
您先别着急感谢我
Let me explain first.
您先听我说
Actually, our bank
其实我们银行
isn't giving you a loan
给你们贷款
as a charity.
也不是做慈善
Additionally,
另外
we need your facilities
您需要把这个
as collateral.
核心车间作为抵押物
Our interest rate will also increase.
我们的利率也会有上浮
If you can accept
如果说这些条件
all these conditions,
您都能接受的话
then we can proceed
那这件事情
with this.
我们可以做
Sure.
我接受
It records all the
您现在看到的就是
bad debts I've been
我在南安县处理的
handling in Nan'an County.
所有不良贷款记录
Among them, the food processing plant
其中这食品加工厂
has already fully repaid
已经全额还清了
their first installment.
他们的第一笔贷款
The other 3 companies
剩下的三家企业
are gradually repaying their loans.
也在陆续还款中
Very impressive.
不错
You've really got
你小子
the talent.
有两把刷子
You flatter me.
您过奖了
I'm just doing my job.
我也只是在其位谋其职
Honestly, I've got
其实这次呀
great help from two
也是多亏了两位
account managers who were able to
能够了解当地情况的
understand the local situation.
客户经理的帮助
There's something I'm hesitant to say.
有句话不知道该不该讲
I hope the headquarters can pay
其实我更希望咱们行里
more attention to staff like them.
能够多关注像他们这样
They're dedicated
坚守在一线的员工
on the front lines,
这些基层员工
and work diligently.
踏踏实实做事
Their tasks are not easy.
其实也很不容易
They deserve our support,
他们是要关心
however,
但是啊
the higher-ups tend to focus more on you.
行里更关注你
In favorable circumstances,
人在顺境里从容啊
you can
是
follow the trend
顺势而为
and
成功
create
是
achievements.
借势而起
However,
但是呢
facing adversity,
在逆境里呀
it's a different story.
就不一样了
Nan'an has
南安县呢
a great number of bad debts.
不良贷款多
It's challenging to conduct business.
业务不好展开
These days,
这段日子
you've been devoted
你没有怨言
to the work without any complaints.
踏踏实实地做事情
Moreover,
而且呀
you've resolved
还把这个
the
任何人
long-standing bad debts
都处理不了的陈年烂账
properly.
都解决了
It's no exaggeration to say
毫不夸张地说
that the results you've achieved
做出的成绩啊
are more impressive
比起你在拓展一部时
than what you've done in S1.
有过之无不及
Thank you, sir.
谢谢领导
Back when you're in S1,
你在分行的时候啊
your president
你们行长
always praised you.
一直夸你
I thought
那会儿啊
he's exaggerating.
我还觉得他夸张
Looking back now,
现在想想啊
he's got a solid point.
他很有眼光
When you reach
希望以后
a higher position,
你到了更高的位置
I hope you can stick
还能够记住
to your principles.
你刚才说的话
Do your best
在其位
in your work.
谋其职
I will definitely not
一定不会辜负总行领导
let you down, sir.
对我的信任
What brings you here?
你怎么来啦
I've got good news that
有个好消息
I wanted to share with you right away.
想要第一时间就告诉你
I've been reassigned back.
我调回星城了
Really?
真的
I didn't expect it to happen so soon.
我也没想到会这么快
These past six months,
这小半年
you've been running around.
你来回奔波
How hard you work!
辛苦你了
Thank you so much these days.
这半年你也辛苦了
Good thing I'm back now.
还好我已经调回来了
So, which branch
那你调回来了以后
have you been assigned to?
被调到哪个支行啦
Ji'an branch.
集安分行
The transfer order's already been issued.
行里的调令已经下来了
I'll be serving as the branch president.
担任行长一职
I'll report in tomorrow.
明天去报到
So should I call you
那我以后是不是要叫你
President Ji from now on?
纪行长了
That's perfectly fine.
也不是不可以哦
Wonderful.
真好
Different paths led to the same goal.
殊途同归
You've achieved what you wanted.
你得到你想要的了
Congrats.
恭喜你
This is good for both of us.
是恭喜我们
Right.
对
That's so good!
恭喜我们
By the way,
对了
are you planning to take a vacation?
有没有打算要休个年假
I do plan to take one.
是要休的呀
What?
怎么
Are you thinking of taking a vacation?
你打算最近休年假
I was thinking
我是想着
we can take a vacation
要是休年假的话
together.
咱们可以一起
Then,
如果你要是休的话
we could go on a trip.
咱们可以一块去度个假
It might not be possible recently.
最近可能不太行
Jing is going on maternity leave.
静姐要休产假
Before that,
生孩子之前
she definitely wants to
她肯定要做出一点
achieve something.
成绩来
She's under great pressure.
她现在压力挺大的
It wouldn't be appropriate
我在这个时候抛弃她
for me to leave her now.
是不是有点不太合适呀
That makes sense.
说得有道理啊
Actually,
其实这事呢
this is your fault.
就怪你
You've set the standards for S1
把拓展一部的标准
too high.
定得太高了
I remember you mentioned vacation
我记得你几个月前
a few months ago.
就说要休年假
Do you have any plans?
是有什么安排吗
No something special.
没什么安排
Now that you're at Ji'an branch,
你去了集安分行
has your workload increased?
是不是事情变多了
Is it hard to spare some time now?
现在也抽不出时间来呀
In any case, if you
总之你要是
have that plan,
有这个计划的话
let me know.
可以跟我说一声
We can coordinate our schedules.
咱们可以把时间对一对
I can adjust to your timing.
我紧着你的时间来
Sounds good!
好呀
I just happened to overhear it
我也就是在前台
at the front desk.
随便听了一嘴
The headquarters
好像总行
sent someone to try out the position.
也派人过来试岗了
But after the trial,
但试了一圈之后呢
they found that Ji Yuheng
还是发现纪昱恒
is the most capable.
比较全能
Finally, the position of president
所以最后行长这个位置
went to him.
还是落到他头上了
His abilities are certainly commendable.
老纪能力肯定没得说
He got reassigned back to the city,
他能调回市区呢
so he doesn't have to travel every day.
不用每天那么折腾
Xiaoning must be relieved.
筱柠肯定也放心了呀
Yes.
是的
You just mentioned
你刚才说是
Ji'an branch.
集安分行
I happen to be looking at
刚好我最近在看
houses nearby.
附近的房子
After, I'll consult him
过两天跟他好好
about home loan options.
咨询一下买房贷款的事
That's a good idea.
可以呀
That area is now
那一片现在
under his management anyway.
反正都归他管
He'll definitely be able to tell you
他肯定能够告诉你
what the best deal is.
怎样更划算
That's true.
好好问一问
No. 6, please.
六号奶茶
Here.
我们的
I didn't expect to find my favorite
真没想到你单位附近
milk tea at your workplace.
还有我爱喝的奶茶呀
There's even a nail salon nearby.
还行还有家美甲店呢
Really?
真的假的
Dad.
爸
Mom.
妈
Yu.
儿子
You've lost weight.
跟过年比你怎么瘦了呀
Is the work too hard for you?
是不是工作太辛苦了
By the way,
对了
your dad has been approved for retirement.
你爸退休已经办下来了
We're thinking
我们琢磨着呀
of renting a place nearby
在这附近租个房子
to spend more time with you.
好好陪陪你
We can also
我们也顺便
explore and have fun here.
在星城好好逛逛玩玩
What's fun
你说这儿附近
around here?
有什么好玩的
Why are you so chatty today?
你今天话怎么这么多呀
Weiyi,
惟依
we've been waiting
我们也等了
for almost half an hour.
小半个钟头了
Do you know
你看
when your dad will arrive?
你爸爸什么时候能来呀
I...
我
I'm sorry.
不好意思啊叔叔
He has a full schedule.
我爸他安排特别满
He's still in a meeting right now.
这会儿还在开会
Today,
今天
he probably won't make it.
恐怕是来不了了
It's OK.
没事
We came
是我们来得
on such short notice.
太临时了
It's not like that.
不是这样的叔叔
Your coming
你和阿姨能来
makes Qi Yu and me very happy.
我和齐郁特别高兴
My dad feels really embarrassed.
我爸他也特别不好意思
He arranged a family suite for you
他在旗下的酒店
at the hotel he owns.
给你们安排了家庭套房
You can stay there
这两天在星城
for the next few days.
你们都可以住那儿
It's very convenient.
特别方便
No need for that.
不必了
We've already
我们自己啊
booked a place.
订了地方
Right.
是
Qi Yu!
齐郁
Dad.
爸
Mom.
妈
We've been working all day,
我和惟依工作一天了
and we haven't had dinner.
也没吃晚饭
You must be hungry from your trip too.
你们一路也肯定饿了吧
How about we eat something?
要不先吃两口东西
Excuse me!
服务员
Please.
上下菜
There's no need to order so much.
其实不用点那么多
We're just common folks.
我们普通人家
Home-cooked meals are okay
平时吃个家常菜什么
for us.
就行了
It's not easy to make money.
平时赚钱也不容易
Ordering so much...
点这么一大桌
Isn't that just
这钱不就
going to
哗 哗 哗地
cost a fortune?
出去了吗
Ma'am,
阿姨
please make yourself at home.
您千万别客气
This is one of the best
这家店在星城
restaurants in the area.
都是数一数二的
Since you both don't come around often,
您和叔叔难得来一次
we should treat you to a good one.
当然得吃点好的了
Sir,
叔叔
Qi Yu told me you love seafood.
听齐郁说您爱吃海鲜
This king crab
这个帝王蟹
is particularly fresh and renowned.
特别新鲜也很有名
It's imported from Northern Europe.
是北欧进口的
Please
叔叔
have a try.
您尝尝
Dad.
爸
What business does Weiyi's family run?
惟依家是做什么生意的
I think it's in
好像是那个
real estate and investment.
地产和投资
What's up, dad?
怎么了爸
You mentioned today
你今天说
that the building she works in
她工作的那个大厦
belongs to her family.
是他们家的
According to what she said,
听她的意思
the hotel is theirs as well?
酒店也是
Yes.
是
How embarrassing!
丢人
You've completely embarrassed
你把我老齐家脸
our family, you know?
都丢尽了知不知道
Calm down.
你好好说
Don't get mad.
别发火
He should thank me for not kicking his ass!
我不揍他就是好的了我
Let me ask you,
我问你啊
are you a good match?
我们家和惟依家般配吗
Is it going to work out?
合适吗
Do you know
你知不知道你们
what this is called?
这叫什么
You wanna marry into her family?
这叫入赘
To put it bluntly,
说难听点
it's called freeloading!
叫吃绝户
Don't talk nonsense.
你瞎说八道什么呢
What?
我瞎说八道
When your son marries her one day,
哪天你儿子真娶了她
and moves in
把行李往人家一搬
with her family,
上她家一住
you know what your relatives will say?
你身边那些亲戚朋友
It will be much worse than I did!
比我说得要难听多了得
You know?
还我胡说八道
Dad,
爸
I'm with Ling Weiyi
我和凌惟依在一起
because we like each other.
就是因为互相喜欢
We're in a serious relationship.
我们是正经恋爱
Let others say
别人愿意怎么说
what they want.
怎么说呗
C'mon!
正经恋爱
Her dad didn't even show up at dinner.
人家爸爸吃饭都不露面
A serious relationship?
你还正经恋爱
Does her whole family even respect you?
他们全家看起你了吗
Besides,
再说了
a dinner costing grands,
一顿饭吃几千块钱
is this how you live seriously?
你们这是正经过日子吗
Are you serious?
是正经过日子吗
Alright, alright.
好了好了
Qi Yu,
齐郁呀
actually, your dad and I
其实我和你爸呢
don't hate Weiyi at all.
也没有不喜欢惟依
This is our first time meeting her.
今天第一次见面啊
We can feel
我们也能感受到
her sincerity.
她的真心和重视
But the gap between our families
但是咱们家跟他们家
is really too big.
这差距实在是太大了
If you get married,
以后你们在一起
it's only a matter of time...
迟早也得
Alright,
行了
enough talk.
别说那么多了
Just break up with her.
赶快分手
Did you hear me?
听见没有
Dad!
爸
We're actually saving money.
我们也有认真攒钱
We wanna make a decent living as well.
就是想以后好好过日子
About the dinner,
还有今天这顿饭
we spent that much 'cause
还不是因为
this is your first visit.
你们第一次来
We wanted to treat you to something nice.
想让你们吃好一点
So you could have a good time.
高兴一点
Was that wrong?
有错吗
Please leave us alone.
我俩的事能不能别管了
I'm begging you.
我求你了别操心了
Please!
行不行
You...
你
Alright, alright.
好了 好了
I...
我
Calm down!
你干什么呀你
What a good son he is!
你看你生的好儿子
Keep calm!
你消消气 消消气
Don't be upset.
好好跟他说啊
Let's talk it out.
好好跟他说
Good morning, Mr. Ji!
行长早
Morning!
早
Busy, huh?
忙着呢
Boss!
领导
Morning!
早
Come on, Mr. Zhao.
来吧赵总
Take a look.
参观一下
This office is much bigger
比之前的办公室
than the previous one.
大了一圈
After all, you're the branch president.
到底是分行行长啊
Your status
身份
is different now.
是不一样了
Here.
来
I've taken this position indeed,
是坐上了这个位置
but to stay secure in it,
但是要想坐稳
I'll need to show some results later.
还得看之后的成果
Come on,
你这话说得
you've already brought me onboard.
你都把我挖过来了
With us working together,
咱们兄弟俩在一块
we'll definitely
并肩作战
be unstoppable.
一定所向披靡
About this position,
这位置啊
since you've already taken it,
既然你也已经坐上了
I'll help you secure it
我就给你扶住椅子
and stay here forever.
让你坐得稳稳当当的
I'm very reassured that you're here.
你能来我很放心
However, you are aware
不过集安分行的情况
of the situation here.
你应该也很清楚
The sales sector
营销板块
is still the key focus
依旧是之后工作的
of our future work.
重中之重
We need to compete for clients with
我们得和全城老牌银行
all the established banks in the city,
去竞争客户
including other branches of Dairui.
包括代瑞的其他分行
So in the coming month,
所以未来这一个月
I hope that while we're exploring
我希望在挖掘
smaller clients,
小体量客户的同时
we can also secure one or two groups
我们能够谈到一到两组
of major ones with a volume
五千万体量以上的
of over 50 million.
大客户
That's when we can truly
那时候才是
build our beachhead.
真正站稳脚跟
No problem.
没问题
I studied it all night last night,
我昨晚彻夜研究了一下
and I found
我发现
a client...
有家客户
Come in.
进
Jing,
静姐
I heard you just vomited.
我刚听说你吐了
I'm alright, really.
没事
Oh my!
我的天
This pregnancy
这一天
has really worn me out.
给我折腾得够呛
How's going with you?
你怎么样
Is the project going well?
项目顺利吗
I need to tell you something important.
我跟你说正事呢要
I recently got in touch with a
我最近接触了一个
long-established private enterprise.
百年老字号的民营企业
Currently,
现在
the presidency has been passed to
总裁的接力棒传到了
the grandson who just
刚从国外回来的
returned from abroad.
孙子辈手上
Is it Mr. Fu
是你之前说的那个
you mentioned earlier?
小付总吗
Yes.
对
Mr. Fu.
就是这个小付总
Under his leadership,
现在呢
he's eager
公司在他手上
to expand the company.
他想要做大做强
So he needs
就非常需要一笔
huge financial support.
不小的资金
If we can establish
如果我们能跟他达成
a partnership with him.
合作协议的话
Jing,
静姐
you'll solidify your position
你这个经理的位置
as the manager.
就坐稳了
Which company is it?
哪家公司啊
Youpin Tea.
优品茶叶
For a company of this scale,
这个体量的公司
I'm sure no one
咱们同行
would want to miss out.
估计没有不想要的吧
Absolutely.
是
I can say that
我感觉
all our competitors
整个星城银行的
in this city
同行们
are getting ready for action.
都在摩拳擦掌啊
Other banks certainly don't want to
其他银行肯定也不想
miss out on such a valuable client.
错过这么优质的客户
We need to take the initiative.
咱们得先下手为强
We're still in the contact stage.
在客户接触阶段
Before we secure the deal,
没有拿下来客户之前
we must remain vigilant about
在外面该说什么
what we should say or shouldn't.
不该说什么
I believe you're
我相信你心里
well aware of this.
应该很清楚
This is a
这是一场
highly competitive info warfare.
竞争激烈的信息战
Therefore, our actions
所以我们的行动
and proposals
还有我们的方案
must remain confidential.
一定要精准保密
The more sensitive the info,
越是核心的材料
the more we need to prevent leaks.
越要提防泄露
We should mislead the competition.
声东击西
This campaign for Ji'an branch
这集安分行
is not just your
不仅是你的
battle for recognition,
立身之战
but also mine.
也是我的
Not to mention the competitors,
别说外面了
even at home,
就算回了家
I promise I won't let slip
我也保证一个字
a single word.
不会透露的
Floral aroma and sweet aftertaste.
花香还有回甘
Nice.
不错
Honey-scented lily.
蜜香铃兰
No wonder it's the top seller.
怪不得卖得这么好
What?
干吗
Is there something hidden in there?
里面藏了什么东西啊
A love letter from another girl?
你给别的女生写的情书
Of course not.
当然不是
Aside from your love letters,
除了你的情书
I won't accept anything from anyone else.
我不会收别人的
Mr. Ji,
纪先生
we're separated
咱们俩
not long ago.
刚刚不在同一个部门
Do you have to be so wary of me?
你就这么提防我呀
You weren't like this before.
以前可不这样
This really hurts my feelings.
你这样我会伤心的
Tell me,
说吧
how much do you need to hit your target?
业绩还差多少
If you're short on clients,
要是缺客户的话
I have some extra ones
我那儿有多的
I can share.
可以分给你
I want the biggest one!
那我要最大的
You and Rao Jing,
你跟饶静
you both have quite the appetite now.
现在胃口不小啊
Obviously, I'll go for the biggest.
要都要了还不要最大的
What are you drinking?
喝的什么呀
Something for beauty and skincare.
美容养颜
Men should stay out of women's affairs.
女人的事男人少管
Mr. Zhou,
周会计
this is Mr. Chen, our VP.
这个是我们陈副行长
He is
是
the supervisor
我们省行
in charge of loans for
专门负责大中型
medium and large enterprises.
企业贷审批的领导
Yesterday, he heard
昨天听说
that Youpin is applying for a loan.
咱们优品要做贷款
He canceled many
今天推掉了好多
important client meetings,
重要的客户
insisting on coming today
说今天必须来
to visit Youpin.
参观一下优品
Thank you
感谢
so much, Mr. Chen.
感谢行长啊
And also,
同时呢
thank you, Ms. Rao.
也谢谢饶总
I heard that Youpin's headquarters
知道咱们优品的总部
has been allocated to Ji'an.
落户到集安
This is actually my first visit here.
我这还是第一次来啊
For enterprises
这有品质
with proven quality
有实力的企业
and strength,
我们区政府
the government must provide
一定会竭尽所能
the most favorable support.
大力扶持
We really appreciate it.
那真是太感谢领导了
Our president, Mr. Fu
我们小付总啊
is eager to drive innovation.
想着做企业革新
In this regard,
这块
your backing will be essential.
少不了您的大力支持
Good.
好
I'll head over right away.
那我这就过去
Mr. Zhou,
那这样周会计
before we came here,
我们来之前呢
we contacted your accounting dept.
跟财务联系了一下
Xiaoning and I
我跟小涂
would like to take a look at
想过去看一下
your financial statements.
财报的情况
So please
所以就麻烦您
bring Mr Chen over first.
带我们陈副行长先过去
- Sure. - Thanks.
行 行 行 好吧
No problem.
那行
Mr Chen,
那陈副行长
please go ahead.
您先上去 好
- Okay. - This way.
好 请
- We'll see you in a bit. - Sure.
咱们一会儿见啊 好
At Dairui, we always uphold
我们代瑞一直都秉持着
the principle of growing
和企业共同成长
and progressing alongside our partners.
共同进步的一个原则
Our collaboration with Youpin
跟优品的合作
will surely be top-notch.
一定会是最优的
Great.
好
Thank you so much.
太感谢了
Let me
那
show you around
我带您到那边
over there.
参观一下
Sure.
好
Jing, you wouldn't believe it,
姐你都不知道
ever since
我们家那位
my husband
自从不跟我
stopped working with me,
并肩作战了以后
he's been trying every trick
天天换着花样地
to get information from me.
在我这刺探军情
Really?
是吗
I should have chosen
早知道我就
a different profession to marry into.
换个职业选老公了
Let me tell you,
我跟你讲
it might be too late
你现在换职业呀
to change professions.
应该是来不及了
How about changing husbands?
但是换老公呢
That's still an option.
我觉得还来得及
No, I'm not willing to do that.
那我不太愿意
I'm telling you,
我跟你讲
my husband is different.
我们家那位就不一样了
He can't keep his mouth shut.
那个嘴根本就把不住门
Do you know what he's dreaming
你知道他昨天晚上做梦
about last night?
跟我聊什么吗
He's talking about pig feed.
他梦里边跟我聊猪饲料
I asked him
我问他
what kind
我说
of pig feed it was,
你这什么猪饲料啊
In his dream,
他在梦里边
he told me that
就跟我对话说
they just finished working
我最近刚服务完一个
with a pig feed client.
猪饲料的客户
Then he explained
然后还把他们银行
all what they're doing,
现在做的
like discounting, factoring,
贴现 保理
and small business loans.
个人经营贷
You know, everything
就咱们银行
our bank does.
做的那一套东西
He covered every detail,
事无巨细地全都告诉我
and even wanted me
在梦里边还要
to join in.
拉我合伙一起干
At least he's open.
还是小赵哥好
Mr. Ji doesn't quite measure up.
纪先生不大行
Open?
好什么好
He's got no subtlety at all.
一点心机没有
Oh, right, I wanna tell you
姐我刚忘了跟你说了
that when I was coming over,
我刚过来的时候发现
I noticed they're dealing with tea,
他们这边是做茶叶的
but they've also
但是有很多
brought in
好像从国外
a lot of coffee sets
买回来一些咖啡杯具
and beans from abroad.
还有咖啡豆
I'm thinking
我在想
maybe they're planning
他们以后
to branch into the coffee business?
是不是想要做咖啡饮啊
Actually,
其实呢
I asked Mr Zhou
我刚才问了
the same question just now.
周会计同样的问题
He told me
他跟我说
that it's simply because
只是因为他的领导
his boss loves coffee.
单纯地喜欢喝咖啡
So he's collected
所以呢就从世界各地
coffee-related items
收了很多
from around the world.
关于咖啡的器具
I thought they're expanding into coffee
我以为是他要做咖啡
and might need more loans.
是不是又需要贷款
Judging by the new equipment,
看刚才那些新设备
they're probably launching
大概是有新产品
some new products.
要上市了
Impressive.
厉害呀
The intel we gathered
我们之前摸到的消息
and what you picked up
和你打听到的
seem spot-on.
几乎没有出入
Well,
怎么
not even calling me boss anymore?
现在连领导都不喊了
Boss.
领导
Mr. Fu is doing well,
那小付总确实可以啊
expanding production lines
刚来就增加生产线
and scaling up operations.
扩大经营
I imagine
我想他之后
his future loan needs
可能贷款的需求和体量
will be substantial.
应该不会小
That's no small potatoes
这可跟你那猪饲料
like your pig feed.
不一样
So, no more sleep-talking
以后做梦的时候
about business deals.
别说梦话
What do you know?
懂啥呀
That's all part of my strategy,
我那是混淆视听
mixing truth
虚虚实实
with fiction.
实实虚虚
You overseas returnees all
你们海归
seem to go against the grain, huh?
是不是都离经叛道的呀
You usually don't follow
家里做什么
your family's business.
自己就偏不做什么
Sounds like
听起来
the client you visited today
你今天跑的客户
is also someone who studied abroad.
也是个海外回来的
I'm talking life,
我跟你聊人生
and you're talking clients,
你跟我聊客户
seriously?
真的是
"Also"?
也是
Does that mean
什么意思啊
your client today
你今天的客户
is a returnee too?
是个海归啊
Young,
年轻
ambitious,
有魄力
and has a strong vision
而且在与企业经营
for business growth
和发展上
and development.
很有自己的想法
You're saying
看来
that he's taken over the family business.
是接手了家族产业
How big is it?
规模多大
Is it so large that you can't
产业这么大吗
reveal a single detail?
一个字都不想透露
One deal
一笔
worth a year's revenue?
顶一年
That's a trade secret.
商业机密
Stingy.
小气鬼
Mr. Fu seems
那个 那个
to have a wide range of hobbies.
小付总爱好挺广啊
A second-generation tea heir
一个茶二代
who's really into coffee, huh?
竟然这么喜欢喝咖啡
Jing, did you notice
姐你注意没有
the shelves in his office?
他办公室那个
They're filled
架子上面
with various brochures of
有好多各种品牌的
fast-moving consumer goods.
快消品介绍
Yes, I did.
我看到了
I also noticed
我看到那桌子上
a couple of books on the table about
还放了两本快消咖啡
the rise of coffee brands.
发家传记呢
Do you think his next move
那你说小付总接下来
might be to develop
他的发展方向
a fast-moving tea drink,
是不是像咖啡一样的
similar to coffee?
快消茶饮
If the company
如果他们的企业
is heading in that direction,
要往这个方向发展的话
it should have been clearly outlined
那他们应该给咱们的
in their loan proposal
银行的贷款企划书里
to our bank.
写得更清楚一些
But it wasn't.
但是并没有
And when we visited yesterday,
而且昨天咱们去的时候
Mr Zhou didn't mention anything.
周会计也没提这事
There might be some internal
好像是他们家
conflicts within his family.
有些内部矛盾
Maybe that's why
有可能因为
it's not convenient for
这些内部矛盾
to disclose something?
不方便
If our assumptions
我说如果是按照咱们俩
are correct,
设想得这样
their loan amount
那他们贷款的数目
should be
应该不止这些
much higher.
要更高
Here.
来
Take a look at this.
你也看看
I had our guy check it out,
我让小周查了一下
the latest equipment
他们最新的
on their production line
生产线上的机器啊
is for a quick-brew tea brand.
是快捷茶饮品牌
So, they're aiming to enter
看来他们要做的
the fast-moving beverage market.
是快消饮品啊
That fits.
那就对上了
I called
我昨儿给他们副总
their VP yesterday,
打了个电话
and they're planning to open stores.
他们打算做一些门店
I think they want to create something
我估计是想做成
like a chain of tea shops,
奶茶店那样
similar to bubble tea stores,
就是针对年轻人的那种
targeting
连锁
the youth market.
快消茶品牌
What's your estimate
那你预估一下
for their
他们大概贷款的体量
loan requirement?
会是多少
50 million?
五千万
Based on their investment plan
看他们的投资计划书
and assessment report...
还有评估报告
Around 100 million.
一个亿左右
Tired?
累了吧
What are you doing here?
怎么在这呀
Waiting for you.
等你啊
Want to take a walk?
一起散散步
Sure.
走
How was work?
怎么样
Exhausting?
工作一天累不累啊
Not bad.
还行吧
But you look a bit worn out,
我看纪行长
Mr Ji.
有点疲惫的样子
What's up?
怎么了
Trouble
跟客户
with the client?
谈得不太顺利呀
We've been working on
根据客户期待的
several financing plans
融资成本
to meet the client's expected costs,
我们做了很多套方案
but we can't get the interest rate down.
但利率一直都下不来
What's the lowest rate
你们分行
your branch
现在利率
can offer right now?
最低能到多少
What?
我们
Well...
我们啊
C'mon,
纪行长
you're really something.
你现在越来越过分了
First, you wait under the streetlight,
又是路灯下等人
then you play the sympathy card,
又是叹气卖惨的
and now you're trying to charm me.
还跟我这儿玩美男计
You're mixing business with pleasure.
你这是以私谋公
So,
那你说
is it working?
你中不中招
Well, since the deal
反正这个客户
is almost closed,
也谈得差不多了
I guess I can share.
跟你说了也没关系
5-year rate,
五年利率
5-year rate at 4.8%?
五年利率四点八
Using the factory as collateral?
抵押物是厂房
Plus a piece of real estate.
还有法人的一套不动产
And the final loan amount?
那最后放款多少
100 million.
一个亿
No,
不
around 70 to 80 million.
七八千万吧
70 to 80 million?
七八千万啊
Really?
七八千万
Sounds like a
那怎么听起来像是一个
100-million client.
亿万体量的大客户啊
I might have
我刚才
exaggerated a bit.
说顺嘴了
Factory as collateral
厂房是抵押物
plus additional real estate,
还要加一套不动产
can the client accept that?
客户能接受啊
And can you afford
利率这么低
to offer such a low rate?
你们自己能接受
No answer?
不说话
I guess I won't get
反正在你嘴里
the truth out of you.
也套不出来实话
I should head back.
我先回去了
Got some work to do.
加班去
Leaving already?
这就走啦
Not going to use your charm anymore?
美男计不使啦
Busy with work,
工作忙成这样
and still keeping secrets.
还互相防着
He's avoiding proposing to me.
我看他是不想跟我求婚
Seriously?
你不至于吧
A privacy screen protector?
还贴了个防偷窥膜
Special times
特殊时期
call for special measures.
特殊手段
This is just too much.
这么防着我
I'm so clumsy.
弄洒了呀
Just my luck,
真是怕什么来什么
running into the same client.
还真撞一起了
Did you see anything?
看出什么心得了吗
What do you mean?
什么意思啊
What could I have seen?
我看出什么了
I saw nothing.
我什么都没看见
You're covering it
你捂得这么严实
all up so well.
我能看见什么呀
I could uncover a lot.
我也可以很不严实
Come on.
走
What are you doing?
你干吗
Since my brother-in-law left,
姐夫离开管理层之后
how many finance staff have resigned?
财务人员走了多少
None of the old ones
之前的老人
are left.
一个不剩
Mr. Fu,
付总
your idea about
您要做快消品
fast-moving consumer goods
这个思路呢
is solid,
确实是不错
but it requires
但是需要
substantial financial backing.
充裕的资金支持
The finance team
财务团队
leaving now
在这个时候离开
is clearly
很明显
a deliberate obstacle.
就是故意为难你
How's the loan negotiation going?
贷款的事谈得怎么样了
Over the past few days,
这几天呢
we've received
我们收到
many proposals from banks,
很多银行的方案
and you've personally met
一些重要的领导
some key figures.
你也都亲自接触过
For now,
综合看下来
Mr Zhou and I think
我和周会计觉得
that two of them stand out.
有两家银行还不错
Yes.
是的
One offers
一个呢
a credit line
他们提出了
with better
信用证的思路
cost-effectiveness,
性价比更高
while the other
另外一个呢
offers
是
a longer loan term
贷款的周期更长
with a repayment schedule
而且呢还款的节奏
more suited to our needs.
对我们来说更加的有利
Here.
来
Ji'an...
集安
Xing City...
星城
Here,
来
take a look.
这 这 这
This place is almost ready.
准现房
It's not huge,
虽然面积不大呢
but both bedrooms face the sun.
但两个卧室都朝阳
Look.
你看
And the transportation is good,
而且交通也方便
right by the expressway.
出门就可以上高架
Looks good.
还挺好的
Let's buy it.
买下来吧
And your parents can live here.
到时候给你爸妈养老住
Weiyi,
惟依
I was thinking
我是想
this could be where we live
我们两个以后住在这里
after we get married.
结了婚
It'll be our home.
这就是我们共同的家了
We'll live at my place
结了婚当然住我那儿
in the city center.
市中心
It's close to both our jobs,
离你我单位都近
so why move further away?
干吗要舍近求远
But isn't that
可那不是
your dad's house?
你爸的房子吗
I wanted us to have something...
我想那不是我们
That could be
我的房子
ours.
就是我们的房子
You just need
你到时候
to move in.
拎包入住就好啦
This place
你看这儿
is small and cramped.
又小又挤的
It'll be uncomfortable,
住起来多不舒服呀
especially
这要是结婚以后
if we
有了孩子
have kids later.
住都住不下
Right.
是
Qi Yu,
齐郁
we can save money
我们日常啊
on daily consumption,
能省就省着点花
but comfort
可是房子
is the top priority for houses.
是每天都要住的
After all,
肯定还是得
we have to live inside every day.
住得舒心最重要吧
Weiyi,
惟依
how about
要不然这样呢
you move in
等房子买了以后
after it's bought?
咱们先搬过来试试看
If you don't think
如果到时候住得
it's good for you,
实在不行你不适应的话
we can...
咱们可以
It won't work for me.
我肯定不适应
I don't understand
我就是挺想不明白的
why you're so stubborn
为什么你老是要在
about this.
这件事情上这么固执啊
We're happy together,
我们明明在一起
aren't we?
很开心很合拍啊
We've solved
那我们现在
the long-distance issue,
异地的问题已经解决了
but now
你有没有觉得
our relationship
恋爱反而谈得
feels heavier.
越来越沉重了呀
But actually,
说白了
it's not a big thing at all.
这事其实很简单
I have a house.
就是我有房子
We could
明明我们可以
live well...
把生活过得很好
But it's not my house,
因为那不是我的房子
and I can't afford that lifestyle.
也不是我能负担的生活
I'm okay with splurging on meals.
吃顿饭贵就贵了
My parents say
我爸妈说
our spending is too high,
咱们消费水平高
but I hold it in.
我就忍了
It's fine.
没事
But taking advantage of your house
那房这事我还占你便宜
makes me feel...
我成什么了
less of a man.
小白脸
I can't respect myself like that,
我自己都看不起自己
you know?
明白吗
Your parents said something?
你爸妈说你了
About me?
说我了
About my spending habits?
说我乱花钱
- Did they? - No.
是不是 没有
Just that our families
就是说咱们两家
have different spending habits,
消费水平不一样
you know?
明白吗
So they
那不就是
don't approve of me?
还是对我不满意呗
I tried so hard to impress them,
我真心实意请他们吃饭
even used
我还破天荒地
my credit card.
刷了信用卡
But now it's my fault?
这反倒都成我的错了
Qi Yu, do you know
齐郁我这段时间
how I've been living lately?
过得什么日子
I have money but can't spend it,
我每天我有钱我不能花
I'm miserable!
我都快憋屈死啦
Weiyi, I know you're frustrated.
惟依我知道你委屈
I know my situation
我知道我现在
isn't great right now,
条件可能没那么好
and this house
可能这个房
is all I can offer.
就是我的全部了
But I wanna
但我想努力
work hard
我想让咱们未来
for our future.
更好一点
You believe me?
明白吗
Don't say you're doing this for me.
你口口声声说是为了我
Really, you're
但其实不过就是
just planning
在你自己能力范围之内
within your limits
去计划着
for your own future.
属于你自己的未来吧
For our future,
如果我要是想要
I'd have to
和你有未来
give up
我就得放着
living in my big house,
大房子我不能住
and spending my money,
有钱我也不能花
or else I'd make you
不然我就会让你
feel bad about yourself.
看不起你自己
So basically,
说白了
you just want me
你不就想让我
to live by your standards.
按照你的标准生活吗
That's not what I mean.
我不是那个意思
Then what do you mean?
那你是什么意思啊
Qi Yu,
齐郁你不觉得
isn't that selfish of you?
你太自私了点吗
We used to be so good together.
我们以前明明那么好
We watched sunsets.
我们一起看落日
He took me to see fish...
他还带我去看鱼
We've done the most
我们看遍了世界
romantic things together.
最浪漫的事
So why does
为什么现在
everything now have to be
非要因为钱啊
about money and houses,
房子啊这些东西的
making us so unhappy?
每天苦哈哈地不开心呢
Why?
到底是为什么呀
Okay, okay,
好了 好了
stop crying.
别哭了
You're embarrassing yourself.
你在这儿丢不丢人啊
Do you know how long
你知道我有多久
it's been since I ate like this?
没有吃这些东西了吗
All I think about
我每天就想着
is saving money
攒钱 攒钱
and planning our life.
怎么把日子过好
But what's the point?
结果到头来呢
My dad doesn't approve,
我爸不看好
his parents are against it.
他爸妈也反对
What's the point
那我们还在一起个
of doing this?
什么劲啊
Just do it
你要难受吧
if you wanna cry.
你哭也行
Maybe
哭完了
you'll feel better after.
会不会心情好点啊
Want me to call Qi Yu?
要不我给齐郁打个电话
No!
不要
I don't wanna see him.
我现在不想看到他
Just thinking about him
我一想到他
talking about all this again
见面又跟我谈这些
makes me sick!
我就烦
You know
你知道他今天
what he said today?
跟我说什么吗
He told me
他说如果
that he'd feel uncomfortable
住在我的房子里边
living in my house,
他就会心里很不舒服
like he'd lose respect for himself.
看不起他自己
But I'm supposed
可是我呢
to lower my standard of living
我就要去为了他的自尊
for his self-esteem?
去降低我的生活水平
He's not even
他根本就
considering me.
也没有为我考虑过
Is that so?
你说是不是啊
To be honest,
我说实话
if he wasn't
他如果真的
considering you,
没有为你考虑
he wouldn't be doing all this.
他不会回来
Buying a house is his way
他买房子
to show that he wanna marry you.
不也是为了想娶你吗
He's not wrong,
其实我觉得他也没有错
but...
只不过
So I'm wrong?
那 那我有错啦
You're not.
你也没有错
Definitely.
你没错
I just
我就是觉得
don't want
根本就不是
that kind of life.
我想要的生活
Look,
你想想
I have everything I need,
我根本就什么都不缺
like a big house,
我有大房子住
and plenty of money.
我也有花不完的钱
Why should I sacrifice
我为什么非要为了他
and struggle
我自力更生
just to make him feel better?
我还苦哈哈地攒钱
I don't
我怎么着
understand this!
我都想不通这事
Waiter!
服务员
Bring us two more bottles,
给我再上两瓶好酒
the best ones.
我要最贵的
C'mon,
好了 好了
stop drinking alone.
你别自己喝了
I'll join you.
我陪你喝
I feel like
我现在就觉得
such an idiot
我为了他
for denying myself
我那么苛待我自己
for his sake.
我简直就是一个大傻子
From now on,
从今往后
I'm going to be
我一定要做回
true to myself.
真正的我自己
As long as you're happy.
你高兴就好
The last time we broke up,
上一次分手
I thought the problem
我以为
was the long distance.
我们的问题是异地
I believe that
我回来了
once this is resolved, it will be fine.
以为这个问题就解决了
But now I realize
可是这一次我发现啊
that sustaining a long-term relationship
维持长远的爱情
isn't just about romance.
光靠浪漫是不行的
It's based on reality too,
也得考虑现实
right?
是吧
Like a stable
你得有一个
and decent job,
稳重体面的工作呀
a house, a car,
你得有房你得有车
and a solid foundation...
有稳定基础
Especially when it comes to
尤其是那个
marriage.
结婚
I was happy about it,
我本来挺高兴的
but now
也不知道为什么
I just feel anxious,
现在就这么焦虑
and stressed.
头疼
You know what I mean?
焦虑你懂吧
I wanna secure
就是想把这些条件啊
all these early,
早点落实好
making preparations
以后能
for a stable future.
踏踏实实过日子
But Weiyi doesn't need that.
可是惟依她不需要
She's got everything.
她条件优秀
Honestly,
家里条件好
she doesn't need
她不需要
to worry about
考虑这些现实问题
the practicalities
那些有的没的
like saving money
什么省吃俭用啊
or living frugally.
攒钱
She did all to match my pace.
都是为了配合我的节奏
But why should she have to
可她为什么要为了我
compromise herself
牺牲自己呢
for me?
成全我
In the end,
到头来
Weiyi is unhappy,
大家都不好都不高兴
and so are
惟依不高兴
my parents.
我爸妈不高兴
And her dad wasn't impressed with me.
惟依她爸对我也不满意
I work hard
我每天
every day,
努力工作上进
trying to improve myself,
每天努力工作上进
but what for?
图什么呢
Am I wrong here?
你说我有错吗
Have you talked about
你刚刚说的这些
this with Weiyi?
跟凌惟依有聊过吗
Probably not, right?
肯定没有吧
I think
我觉得你们
you need to communicate.
需要的是沟通
Without talking it out,
这种事情不沟通
you'll never find a solution.
就永远找不到解决办法
A solution?
解决
What solution?
你告诉我怎么解决
There isn't one.
没法解决
I can't become
我也不可能
wealthy overnight,
一夜变得很有钱
or expect her to lower her standards.
也不能要求她向下
What's that phrase again?
那个词怎么说来着
Downward compatibility,
向下兼容
right?
对吧
Honestly,
其实我觉得
sometimes parents' worries
父母有时候担忧啊
aren't baseless.
也不是没道理的
They have a point.
它确实有道理
Neither of us is wrong.
我们两个都没错
We're just...
我们就是
Here.
来
It's been so long,
事情都过去这么久
and there's still no sign from him.
他怎么一点动静都没有
Does he think that just 'cause
该不会是觉得
things have already gone this far,
生米煮成熟饭
he doesn't need to propose?
就不用求婚了
Dinner's ready.
开饭了
What are you looking for?
找什么呢
My notebook.
笔记本
I like to review it often.
经常翻一翻
It helps me stay on track.
对自己有帮助
That's good.
还得是小涂
Always refreshing your knowledge.
温故而知新啊
Experience might
很多事情时间长了
let you
有经验了
coast on clever tricks
也可以用小聪明
after a while.
糊弄过去
But
但是
there are key steps
这该走的程序
and moments
跟必要的节点
that you just can't skip.
是一个也不能少的
Right,
你说对吧
Mr Ji?
纪行长
Absolutely.
那是当然
Why the sudden talk?
怎么突然说这些
Let's eat.
吃饭吧